#### Contact

somayeh.yarahmadi@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/somayehyarahmadi-357aab5b (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

Matlab

Simulink

Microsoft Word

#### Languages

**English** 

Persian

#### Certifications

Using Python to Access Web Data

Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

**Python Basics** 

Python Functions, Files, and Dictionaries

#### Honors-Awards

Exceptional B.S. talent

Exceptional M.S. talent

M.Sc. Fellowship

#### **Publications**

Current harmonics reduction of nonlinear load by using active power filter based on improved sliding mode control

Novel Control Strategy for VSI and CSI Active Filters and Comparing These Two Types of Filters

Parallel Active Filter based on Improved Sliding Mode Control

Robust control design for an islanded microgrid using H2 and H∞

# Somayeh Yarahmadi

Graduate Research Assistant at Virginia Tech Blacksburg

## Summary

Four years ago, I did a project for the dynamics of power systems course on the clustering of coherent synchronous generators by support vector machine. This project got me interested in Machine Learning. It was very impressive to me that a machine could be smart similar to a person and solve the problem even easier and more accurately than a human. I decided to expand my knowledge in this field by taking online courses and reading popular books and blogs. Through these studies, I found that Deep Learning is much more powerful. Before I started learning Deep Learning, since I knew Python programming language was extremely useful in deep learning because of its simplicity and extensive libraries and frameworks, I decided to improve my programming skills. Therefore I took a couple of online courses and used the HackerRank website to practice Python practically that I received the 1st rank in that. After I was been confident in my Python skills, I started learning Deep Learning by taking an online course and get its certificate. Certainly, this is not the end of my willingness to learn this field, and I have plans to release my open-source codes and their documents and create a deep learning blog to share my experiences and knowledge with others.

## Experience

Virginia Tech

1 year 11 months

Graduate Research Assistant August 2020 - Present (1 month)

Research Scholar October 2018 - August 2020 (1 year 11 months) United States

Islamic Azad University Lecturer

January 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 8 months)
Dorood

Payame Noor University (Distance Education)

Lecturer

August 2013 - May 2015 (1 year 10 months)

Dorood

**Shahrekord University** 

Lecturer

January 2011 - May 2013 (2 years 5 months)

Shahrekord

### Education

Virginia Tech

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Electrical and Electronics

Engineering · (2020 - 2024)

Udacity

Programming for Data Science with Python Nanodegree, Computer

Science · (2020 - 2020)

Udacity

Data Analyst Nanodegree, Computer Science · (2020 - 2020)

University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj

Doctor of Philosophy - PhD, Electrical and Electronics

Engineering · (2015 - 2020)

Shahrekord University

Master's Degree · (2010 - 2012)